{
    "id": "065f1dd6219744bbad178f8d97bbbf8d",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The higher you climb ...............................................",
            "description": "In this structure with two comparative expressions, we use the same pattern in both clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "it gets colder",
                "it is getting colder",
                "the colder it gets"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The more he reads, the ............................................. he understands.",
            "description": "Less is the comparative form of little. Lesser means smaller. ",
            "answers": [
                "less",
                "little",
                "lesser"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The government should pay attention to the problems of .....................................................",
            "description": "The unemployed means all unemployed people. The article 'the' is required in this expression. ",
            "answers": [
                "unemployed",
                "the unemployed",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "They saw the criminal ....................................................... open the door.",
            "description": "The infinitive is used without to after the verb see.",
            "answers": [
                "break",
                "to break",
                "broke"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The strike ........................................................ if the workers' demands had been granted.",
            "description": "A passive verb is required here. In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "would have called off",
                "would be called off",
                "would have been called off"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ........................................... more carefully, you wouldn't make so many mistakes.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "listened",
                "listen",
                "had listened"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I consider ............................................... to have this opportunity of welcoming you.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "a privilege",
                "it a privilege",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The leader said that it would be unwise .............................................. the democratic demands of the people.",
            "description": "Negative forms are usually made by putting not before the infinitive. ",
            "answers": [
                "to not accept",
                "not to accept",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He said that the climate ................................................. his health.",
            "description": "A past tense in the main clause is almost always followed by a past tense in the subordinate clause.",
            "answers": [
                "has affected",
                "was affected",
                "had affected"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "As soon as the clients .................................................., he locked up his office and went home.",
            "description": "A past tense in the main clause is almost always followed by a past tense in the subordinate clause.",
            "answers": [
                "have left",
                "were leaving",
                "had left"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The leaning tower of Pisa ...................................................... more and more every year.",
            "description": "We use the present perfect continuous to talk about an action or situation that started in the past and has continued up to the present. ",
            "answers": [
                "leans",
                "is leaning",
                "has been leaning"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He brushed ............................................. all the plans that I had carefully formulated.",
            "description": "To brush something aside is to dismiss it. ",
            "answers": [
                "aside",
                "up",
                "on"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}